<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infra As Code Terraform on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/terraform/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infra As Code Terraform on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure AWS CLI - Windows</title>
      <link>http://example.org/terraform/cli_setup_windows/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/terraform/cli_setup_windows/index.html</guid>
      <description>Setup AWS CLI Follow below steps for installation of AWS CLI on Windows Operating System
Verify Python installation: AWS CLI requires Python to be installed on your Windows laptop. Open the Command Prompt by searching for &amp;ldquo;Command Prompt&amp;rdquo; in the Windows Start menu.
Then, type the following command and press Enter to check if Python is installed:
python --version If Python is not installed, download and install the latest version of Python from the official website (https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure AWS CLI - Mac OS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/terraform/cli_setup_macos/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/terraform/cli_setup_macos/index.html</guid>
      <description>Setup AWS CLI To set up the AWS Command Line Interface (CLI) on a MacBook, you can follow these steps:
Install Python: AWS CLI requires Python to be installed on your MacBook. By default, macOS comes with a pre-installed version of Python. Open the Terminal application (you can find it in the &amp;ldquo;Utilities&amp;rdquo; folder within &amp;ldquo;Applications&amp;rdquo;) and run the following command to check if Python is installed: python --version If Python is not installed, you can download and install it from the official Python website (https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Terraform - Windows</title>
      <link>http://example.org/terraform/terraform_setup_windows/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/terraform/terraform_setup_windows/index.html</guid>
      <description>To install Terraform on a Windows system, you can follow these steps:
Download the Terraform binary:
Open a web browser and go to the Terraform website at https://www.terraform.io/downloads.html. Scroll down to the &amp;ldquo;Terraform Core&amp;rdquo; section and locate the Windows version. Click on the appropriate 64-bit or 32-bit download link depending on your system architecture. This will download a ZIP file containing the Terraform binary. Extract the Terraform binary:
Locate the downloaded ZIP file, right-click on it, and select &amp;ldquo;Extract All&amp;rdquo; from the context menu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Terraform - Mac OS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/terraform/terraform_setup_macos/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://example.org/terraform/terraform_setup_macos/index.html</guid>
      <description>To install Terraform on macOS using Homebrew, you can follow these steps:
Open the Terminal application. You can find it in the &amp;ldquo;Utilities&amp;rdquo; folder within the &amp;ldquo;Applications&amp;rdquo; folder.
Install Homebrew (if not already installed): In the Terminal, paste the following command and press Enter:
/bin/bash -c &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)&amp;#34; This command will install Homebrew, a package manager for macOS.
Install Terraform: In the Terminal, run the following command to install Terraform using Homebrew: brew install terraform This command will download and install the latest version of Terraform from the Homebrew repository.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>